# **Rigelle Cruz**

**FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER** 

As a full-stack web developer, I am driven to utilise my problem-solving skills and technical knowledge to build creative solutions that can make a difference in people's lives. I thrive in both collaborative and independent settings, where I can successfully contribute my knowledge and skills in creating amazing digital experiences.

022 172 4367 **LinkedIn/**rigelle-cruz

New Zealand Citizen

Auckland, New Zealand rigellecruz@gmail.com

LinkedIn/rigelle-cruz
GitHub/rigelle-cruz
Portfolio/rigelle-cruz

# **PERSONAL SKILLS**

### **Problem Solving**

- Employed creative thinking and technical expertise in both frontend and backend of software development.
- Proficient in integrating third-party APIs and services, solving challenges related to data format and authentication.
- Diagnosed and eliminated bugs in an e-commerce application, combining problem-solving skills with proficiency in web technologies for swift issue resolution.

#### Attention to Detail

- Demonstrated meticulous attention to detail throughout web development projects, especially in code implementation.
- Implemented automated unit testing to a music-sharing app, ensuring each unit of code performs its intended function correctly.
- Meticulously tested and assembled circuits with attention-to-detail, while maintaining high-quality standards for electronics.

#### **Collaboration & Communication**

- Collaborated seamlessly within agile teams, fostering effective communication and productive teamwork.
- Actively contributed to technical design in development projects and developed strong relationship-building skills.
- Responded promptly to client inquiries, delivering solutions and ensuring client satisfaction.

# **Versatility and Adaptability**

 Quick learner and adaptable to new technologies and frameworks as project requirements evolve.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript

**TypeScript** 

React.js

Redux.js

**HTML** 

CSS, Tailwind

Frontend & Backend

Frameworks

Familiarity with version control

systems (Git)

Node.js

SQlite3 with Knex

**REST APIs** 

Jest

Vite

Test automation

Agile & Scrum methodologies

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

MARCH 2023 - JULY 2023

Dev Academy Aotearoa - Auckland

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (level 6)

MARCH 2019 - FEBRUARY 2022

The University of Auckland - Auckland

Bachelor of Arts - Majoring in Communications

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2023 - MAY 2024

# Outsourced Marketing - Auckland (Remote)

# Web Developer & Digital Marketer

- Collaborated with remote teams to successfully deliver projects.
- Designed and developed responsive WordPress websites, enhancing client online presence.
- Created visually compelling ad tiles for marketing campaigns.
- Implemented SEO strategies to improve search rankings and boost organic traffic.

#### MARCH 2023 - JULY 2023

# **Dev Academy Aotearoa** - Auckland

15-week (70 hrs/week) full-stack software development boot-camp, providing a realistic team environment in an agile setting.

# SEPTEMBER 2022 - DECEMBER 2022

# PowerShield Limited - Auckland

# MARCH 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

# Hollywood Metro - Auckland

#### **MARCH 2022**

The Red Bow - Remote

# **Full Stack Developer - Student**

- Efficiently integrated front-end and back-end components in an event organiser app using RESTful APIs for client-server communication.
- Front-end lead in final group project, developing an e-commerce website, enhancing user experience using React to create an intuitive interface.
- Employed responsive web design principles and techniques to address diverse user needs and challenges.
- Conducted thorough testing using Vite and Jest on server routes in a music-sharing app, to ensure reliability and functionality.

#### **Electronics Tester & Electronics Assembler**

- Tested and assembled circuits.
- Demonstrated ability to ensure top-notch quality and effectively collaborate within a team.
- Successfully resolved technical issues with PCBs during the testing phase, ensuring quality products for clients.

#### Cafe Worker & Barista

- Demonstrated ability to adhere to stringent food quality standards while preparing food and beverages.
- Customer service and cash handling.

# **Volunteer Graphic Designer**

- Conceptualising and producing original designs and illustrations.
- Marketing the charity's values for their social media platform.
- Experience in wireframing and creating mockups using Figma, Photoshop & Illustrator